materialdatacenter.com 2019-07-15

# 

**Privacy Policy**  
Any personal information provided to or gathered by this website is controlled by:  
M-Base Engineering + Software GmbH   
Rotter Bruch 17   
52068 Aachen   
Germany

Phone.: +49-241-92786190  
Fax: +49-241-927861969  
Email: [privacy@m-base.de](mailto:privacy@m-base.de)

 **Collecting general data**  
When you visit our website, general information is collected automatically. This information (server logfiles) may contain the type of your web browser, the used operating system and similar data. This information does not allow conclusions about your person. This information is technically necessary to correctly deliver the contents of web pages requested by you and is mandatory when using the internet. Anonymous information of this kind is statistically evaluated by us to optimize our internet presence and the underlying technology. For security reasons and in order to avoid misuse of our systems, we store IP addresses temporarily. In case of misuse, we reserve the right to block out certain IP addresses. All information collected by our systems is stored on servers in Germany. 

**Registration**  
When registering for the use of our personalized services, some personal information will be collected, such as name, address, telephone number and email address. If you are registered, you can access content and services that we offer only to registered users. Registered users may be informed about system related information, such as changes in the scope of the product, technical circumstances or special offers. Registered users also have the option of changing or deleting the data provided at registration at any time, if this is compliant with the execution of our contract. We do not pass personal data on to third parties. To protect the security of your data during transmission, we use state-of-the-art encryption techniques (e. g. SSL) over HTTPS. 

**Deletion or blocking of data**  
We adhere to the principles of data avoidance and data minimization. Therefore, we only store your personal data for as long as necessary to achieve the purposes mentioned here or as required by the various retention periods prescribed by law. After discontinuation of the respective purpose or expiration of these deadlines, the corresponding data are routinely blocked or deleted in compliance with the legal requirements. 

**Your rights to information, rectification, restriction, erasure and opposition**  
At any time you have the right to obtain information on all of your stored personal data. Likewise, you have the right to rectification, restriction or, apart from the required data storage for business processings and the legal archiving obligation, deletion of your personal data. To contact us in this matter, please use the above-mentioned email address. You can make changes or revoke your consent by notifying us with effect for the future. 

**Use of Matomo**  
This website uses Matomo (formerly Piwik), an open source software for the statistical evaluation of visitor access. Matomo uses so called "Cookies", text files that are stored on your computer and allow us to analyze the use of our website. The IP address is immediately anonymized after processing and before retention. 

**General information about the use of Cookies**  
Our software uses so called "Session-Cookies", text files that are stored on your computer. Cookies are necessary for the operation of our systems. These Cookies do not store any personal data. You have the option to disable the use of cookies by your browser software. Please note that not all functions of this website may be available for this respective setting. 

**Change of our privacy policy**  
We reserve the right to change this privacy policy from time to time to ensure that it complies with current legal requirements or to implement changes to our services in the privacy policy, such as the introduction of new services. Your proximate visit will be subject to the new privacy policy. 

Revision: March 2018
